<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>documentation-theme-jekyll</title>
        <description>This is the documentation of the &amp;tau; Project.</description>
        <link>/</link>
        <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 11:45:46 +0100</pubDate>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 11:45:46 +0100</lastBuildDate>
        <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
        
        <item>
            <title>A new &amp;tau; documentation</title>
            <description>&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-jekyll&quot;&gt;1. Jekyll&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The previous tool for the τ documentation was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gitbook.com/&quot;&gt;Gitbook&lt;/a&gt;.
It was a bad choice :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gitbook used to be Free and Open Source (Apache license). But the free project is now deprecated. It has not been maintened for three years.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gitbook is now developed by a little french company but is not Open Source anymore. This happens with Free software not protected with a strong Free and Open Source license (GPL). This is what happens with license like MIT or Apache which are bad licenses.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;My thinking is that Flutter Sound must &lt;strong&gt;NOT USE PROPRIETARY SOFTWARE&lt;/strong&gt;. This is a political choice.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gitbook is buggy. When we include an HTML page in the documentation, the page hyperlinks point to Github instead of the documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Impossible to include the pages produced by Dartdoc inside our documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Free/Open Source version of Gitbook has High Security Alerts from Github. This is not acceptable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The major challenge was to find a tool that can integrate smoothly the Dartdoc Documentation. The Dartdoc documentation is just HTML pages instead of Markdown.
I investigated many documentation tools (Hugo, Gatsby, JustTheDoc, docsy, docusaurus, …), but all those tools was not compatible with Dartdoc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really wanted the following features :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The user can browse the API reference documentation (&lt;a href=&quot;dartdoc.html&quot;&gt;Dartdoc Documentation&lt;/a&gt;) from the Flutter Sound documentation without opening a new browser tab, and return to the flutter documentation with the Browser Back button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The API reference documentation must display the Flutter Sound documentation top navigation bar.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The user can display the left navigation bar on Dartdoc pages, so that he/she will never be lost.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The user can choice to display or hide this left navigation bar if he/she has a narrow screen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only tool I found which met my required features is &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://idratherbewriting.com/documentation-theme-jekyll/index.html&quot;&gt;Documentation Theme for Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;.
This tool is not perfect. Far from that. But it allows the pages produced by Dartdoc to be integrated inside our documentation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that this time the choice is correct : I spent too much time on the documentation tool, instead of the documentation content itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please, let ne know if you have remarks on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-the-version-74&quot;&gt;2. The Version 7.4&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did a terrible mistake : the master branch is now named 7.4.9 instead of 6.4.9 Impossible to correct that on pub.dev: a commit is for ever. I am confused :-( .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suggest that Flutter Sound users stay on 6.4 .  The version 6.4 will be the real current version released and supported.
The version 7.x  will be the future version and will not be background compatible with V6.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-a-roadmap&quot;&gt;3. A Roadmap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, the Flutter Sound issues are a complete mess.
Everybody create new issues sometimes for bugs, sometimes for asking help, sometimes to request new features.
But nobody can have a clear visibility of the actual situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually there is 71 issues open. And probably there will be more next week. I cannot manage that all by myself alone.
The deficiency of Flutter Sound developers is a big problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not satisfied with the way Github manage the &lt;em&gt;issues&lt;/em&gt;. I am thinking to setup a real Bug Tracker.
Something like Mantis, Trac, Bugzilla or Jira. But I worry that those tools are really good to manage
a project with a real team. Actually Flutter Sound has no team. So nobody to be managed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suggest that for now we keep &lt;em&gt;Github&lt;/em&gt; and use &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/dooboolab/flutter_sound/projects/3&quot;&gt;the Projects feature&lt;/a&gt; for trying
to have a better visibility of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;what must be done (first column),&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;what is planned (second column),&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;what is in progress (third column)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;and what is done (fourth column).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will try to keep the number of issues planned (second column) not too high, and order this column from &lt;strong&gt;high&lt;/strong&gt; priority to &lt;strong&gt;low&lt;/strong&gt; priority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When an issue will be registered in the &lt;em&gt;Project&lt;/em&gt; table, I will close it.
An issue closed will not be necessary fixed, but we will be sure that it is entered somewhere in the planning.
Note: the &lt;em&gt;Project&lt;/em&gt; table can point to close issues, so this is not a problem to close them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something not clear for me, is how the Flutter Sound users can influence the issues that are planned, and the priority of those planned issues.
There is three possibilities :&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Flutter Sound user can post remarks in issues to help me to know what is important or not&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Flutter Sound user can use the &lt;em&gt;Discussions&lt;/em&gt; as a forum to discuss what must me done.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use the Github Wiki&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do not understand why the Github &lt;em&gt;Discussions&lt;/em&gt; feature is not used by Flutter Sound users.
If necessary, we can setup a real forum like PhpBB, MyBB, or Discourse. But probably better to try to use the current tool (Github) before seting up something new.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
            <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
            <link>/newdoc-post.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="true">/newdoc-post.html</guid>
            
            <category>jekyll</category>
            
            
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
